A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Education and Research Division, Office Files of Fred E. Crossland FA713
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Education Files, 1970-1980; I
  - Venture Fund Program Site Visits, B
    - South
      - Bethany College, 1971 September - March (Box 4, Folder 273)
      - Centere College of Kentucky, 1971 October - January (Box 4, Folder 274)
      - Coker College, 1972 January (Box 4, Folder 275)
      - University of Delaware, 1971 April (Box 4, Folder 276)
      - Emory University, 1971 April (Box 4, Folder 277)
      - Florida Atlantic University, 1972 January (Box 4, Folder 278)
      - Florida Presbyterian College, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 279)
      - Florida Southern College, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 280)
      - Furman University, 1971 December (Box 4, Folder 281)
      - Georgetown University, 1971 October (Box 4, Folder 282)
      - George Washington University, 1971 October (Box 4, Folder 283)
      - Hollins College, 1971 October (Box 4, Folder 284)
      - Louisiana St. Univ. (New Orleans), 1971 December (Box 4, Folder 285)
      - Millsaps College, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 286)
      - National Lab. for Higher Ed., 1971 December (Box 4, Folder 287)
      - New College, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 288)
      - Univ. of N. C. (Charlotte), 1971 April (Box 4, Folder 289)
      - University of Richmond, 1971 October (Box 4, Folder 290)
      - Rollins College, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 291)
      - University of South Florida, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 292)
      - University of the South, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 293)
      - Stetson University, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 294)
      - Transylvania University, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 295)
      - Union College, 1971 December - 1970 November (Box 4, Folder 296)
      - University of Tampa, 1971 January (Box 4, Folder 297)
      - University of West Florida, 1972 January (Box 4, Folder 298)
      - Wake Forest University, 1971 March (Box 4, Folder 299)
      - Washington College, 1971 October - March (Box 4, Folder 300)
      - William & Mary College, 1971 October (Box 4, Folder 301)
      - Wofford College, 1970 September (Box 4, Folder 302)
    - Venture Fund Program Candidates Outside Mainland United States, 1972 August (Box 4, Folder 303)
    - August 1974 Venture Fund Program Conference at Nordic Hills, 1974 September - May (Box 4, Folder 304)
  - American Undergraduate Education Survey Files, C
    This sub-series is further divided into three sections: American Undergraduate Education Questionnaire and Responses, American Undergraduate Education Questionnaire - Final Comments, and American Undergraduate Education MiniProfiles of Universities. The files are arranged alphabetically by name of institution. Within each folder, the correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order.
    - American Undergraduate Education Questionnaire and Responses
      - American Undergraduate Education Questionnaire and Respondents, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 305)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. I-A (Box 4, Folder 306)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. I-B (Box 4, Folder 307)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. I-C (Box 4, Folder 308)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. I-D (Box 4, Folder 309)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. II-A (Box 4, Folder 310)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. II-B (Box 4, Folder 311)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. II-C (Box 4, Folder 312)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. II-D (Box 4, Folder 313)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. III-A (Box 4, Folder 314)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. III-B (Box 4, Folder 315)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. III-C (Box 4, Folder 316)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. III-D (Box 4, Folder 317)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. IV-A (Box 4, Folder 318)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. IV-B (Box 4, Folder 319)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. IV-C (Box 4, Folder 320)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. IV-D (Box 4, Folder 321)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. V-A (Box 4, Folder 322)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. V-B (Box 4, Folder 323)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. V-C (Box 4, Folder 324)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. V-D (Box 4, Folder 325)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VI-A (Box 4, Folder 326)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VI-B (Box 4, Folder 327)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VI-C (Box 4, Folder 328)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VI-D (Box 4, Folder 329)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VII-A (Box 4, Folder 330)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VII-B (Box 4, Folder 331)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VII-C (Box 4, Folder 332)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VII-D (Box 4, Folder 333)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VIII-A (Box 4, Folder 334)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VIII-B (Box 4, Folder 335)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VIII-C (Box 4, Folder 336)
      - AUE Questionnaire and Selected Responses, Question No. VIII-D (Box 4, Folder 337)
    - American Undergraduate Education Questionnaire - Final Comments
      - Academy for Educational Develop, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 338)
      - University of Alabama, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 339)
      - Alderson Broaddus College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 340)
      - American Council on Education, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 341)
      - Antioch College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 342)
      - Applachian State University, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 343)
      - Assoc. of American Colleges, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 344)
      - Austin College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 345)
      - Benedict College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 346)
      - Chatham College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 347)
      - Clark College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 348)
      - Coe College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 349)
      - Colby College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 350)
      - Colorado College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 351)
      - Dartmouth College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 352)
      - Earlham College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 353)
      - East Montana College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 354)
      - Eckerd College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 355)
      - Education Comm. of the States, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 356)
      - ERIC/Higher Education, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 357)
      - Grand Valley State Colleges, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 358)
      - Hamline University, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 359)
      - Hendrix College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 360)
      - Hobart & Wm. Smith College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 361)
      - Immaculate Heart College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 362)
      - Kent State University, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 363)
      - Univ. of Massachusetts (Boston), 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 364)
      - Massachusetts Inst. of Technology, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 365)
      - Michigan State University, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 366)
      - Minnesota Metro. St. College, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 367)
      - College Misericordia, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 368)
      - University of Montana, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 369)
      - University of New Orleans, 1975 July (Box 4, Folder 370)
      - Otterbein College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 371)
      - Pace University, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 372)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 373)
      - Roosevelt University, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 374)
      - St. Augustine's College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 375)
      - St. John's College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 376)
      - St. Lawrence University, 1975 August (Box 5, Folder 377)
      - St. Louis University, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 378)
      - Southern Assoc. of Coll. & Sch., 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 379)
      - SUNY (Albany), 1975 August (Box 5, Folder 380)
      - Swarthmore College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 381)
      - Univ. of Tennessee (Martin), 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 382)
      - Vanderbilt University, 1975 August (Box 5, Folder 383)
      - Wellesley College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 384)
      - University of West Florida, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 385)
      - Whittier College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 386)
      - Univ. of Wisconsin (Green Bay), 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 387)
      - Worcester Polytechnic Institute, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 388)
    - American Undergraduate Education MiniProfiles of Universities
      - Mini-Profiles – General, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 389)
      - University of Alabama, 1974 November - April (Box 5, Folder 390)
      - Alderson Broaddus College, 1974 December - May (Box 5, Folder 391)
      - Alverno College, 1974 December - May (Box 5, Folder 392)
      - Antioch College, 1974 December - April (Box 5, Folder 393)
      - Applachian State University, 1974 November - May (Box 5, Folder 394)
      - Austin College, 1974 December - May (Box 5, Folder 395)
      - Bowdoin College, 1974 December - January (Box 5, Folder 396)
      - Univ. of California (Santa Cruz), 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 397)
      - Centre College of Kentucky, 1974 November - April (Box 5, Folder 398)
      - Chatham College, 1975 June - 1974 March (Box 5, Folder 399)
      - Coe College, 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 400)
      - Colby College, 1974 December (Box 5, Folder 401)
      - Colorado College, 1974 December - April (Box 5, Folder 402)
      - Dartmouth College, 1974 December - July (Box 5, Folder 403)
      - Earlham College, 1974 December - September (Box 5, Folder 404)
      - East Montana College, 1974 December - May (Box 5, Folder 405)
      - Eckerd College, 1974 December - April (Box 5, Folder 406)
      - Grand Valley St. Colleges, 1975 January - 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 407)
      - Hamline University, 1978 July - 1974 March (Box 5, Folder 408)
      - Hendrix College, 1975 February - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 409)
      - Hobart & Wm. Smith College, 1975 July - June (Box 5, Folder 410)
      - Immaculate Heart College, 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 411)
      - Kent State University, 1975 February - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 412)
      - Michigan State University, 1975 February - 1974 June (Box 5, Folder 413)
      - Minnesota Metro. St. College, 1975 July - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 414)
      - College Misericordia, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 415)
      - University of Montana, 1974 August - July (Box 5, Folder 416)
      - University of Nebraska, 1974 November - September (Box 5, Folder 417)
      - University of New Orleans, 1975 February - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 418)
      - Ottawa University, 1975 April - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 419)
      - Otterbein College, 1975 March - 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 420)
      - Pace University, 1975 July - 1974 March (Box 5, Folder 421)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 422)
      - Prescott College, 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 423)
      - Roosevelt University, 1975 March - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 424)
      - St. John's College, 1975 May - 1974 July (Box 5, Folder 425)
      - St. Lawrence University, 1975 February - 1973 November (Box 5, Folder 426)
      - Sangamon State University, 1975 May - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 427)
      - University of South Carolina, 1975 May - 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 428)
      - Swarthmore College, 1975 July - 1974 October (Box 5, Folder 429)
      - Univ. of Tennessee (Martin), 1975 (Box 5, Folder 430)
      - Vanderbilt University, 1975 June - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 431)
      - University of Vermont, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 432)
      - University of Washington, 1975 September - 1974 September (Box 5, Folder 433)
      - Wellesley College, 1975 July (Box 5, Folder 434)
      - Univ. of West Florida, 1975 June - 1974 April (Box 5, Folder 435)
      - Whitman College, 1975 July - 1974 July (Box 5, Folder 436)
      - Univ. of Wisconsin (Green Bay), 1975 July - 1974 May (Box 5, Folder 437)
      - Worcester Polytechnic Institute, 1975 July - 1974 September (Box 5, Folder 438)
      - Fred E. Crossland Book (Box 5, Folder 439)
  - Planning for the 1980's, D
    These files consist of correspondence and related materials concerning state planning educational initiatives. They are arranged alphabetically by name of state. Within each folder, the correspondence is arranged by name of institution, and is in reverse chronological order.
    - General File, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 440)
    - Connecticut (Univ. of Bridgeport), 1980 September - February (Box 6, Folder 441)
    - University of Connecticut, 1979 November (Box 6, Folder 442)
    - Conn. Bd. of Higher Education, 1981 March - 1979 November (Box 6, Folder 443)
    - Conn. Conference of Indep. Coll., 1980 May - 1979 October (Box 6, Folder 444)
    - University of Hartford, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 445)
    - Sacred Heart University, 1980 June - May (Box 6, Folder 446)
    - Illinois, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 447)
    - Indiana, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 448)
    - Iowa, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 449)
    - Massachusetts, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 450)
    - Michigan, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 451)
    - Minnesota, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 452)
    - New Jersey, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 453)
    - New York, 1981-1979 (Box 6, Folder 454)
    - Ohio, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 455)
    - Pennsylvania, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 456)
    - Rhode Island, 1980-1979 (Box 6, Folder 457)
    - Wisconsin, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 458)
    - Memos to the 13 States, 1981 January - 1979 October (Box 6, Folder 459)
  - Subject Files, E
    This sub-series consists of correspondence and materials as they relate to FF educational activities. Within each folder, the files are arranged in reverse chronological order.
    - Minority Individual Awards Programs, 1978 August - 1976 December (Box 7, Folder 460)
    - Minority Individual Awards Programs, 1976 December - May (Box 7, Folder 461)
    - Evaluation - Minority Awards Washington, D.C. Meeting, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 462)
    - HERI - Evaluation of Fellowship Programs, 1978 November - July (Box 7, Folder 463)
    - HERI - Evaluation of Fellowship Programs, 1978 June - 1977 September (Box 7, Folder 464)
    - Individual Awards Program Paper, 1978 May - April (Box 7, Folder 465)
    - Doctoral and Advanced Study Programs, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 466)
    - Doctoral and Advanced Study Programs, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 467)
    - Ford Foundation Fellowships for Minority Students, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 468)
    - Ford Foundation Fellowships for Minority Students, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 469)
    - Advanced Study Fellows (FF) Minority Students, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 470)
    - Ford Foundation Black Administrator Awards, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 471)
    - Ford Foundation Ethnic Dissertation Fellowships, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 472)
    - Ford Foundation Individual Study Awards (Bell Committee) and IRS Filing Procedures, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 473)
    - Ford Foundation Individual Awards Survey (General), 1972-1969 (Box 7, Folder 474)
    - Bundy Memo - Response to Trustees Questions, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 475)
    - HE&R Planning and Budgeting, 1977 July - 1976 December (Box 7, Folder 476)
    - HE&R Programmatic Efforts to Improve University Finance and Management, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 477)
    - Urban Universities, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 478)
    - E&R Discussion: Two-Year Colleges, Taxes, & Equity, 1977 August - March (Box 7, Folder 479)
    - School Finance, 1978 March (Box 7, Folder 480)
    - School Finance Conference - San Antonio, Texas, 1980 May - February (Box 7, Folder 481)
    - School Finance Conference - Aspen, Colorado, 1976 November (Box 7, Folder 482)
    - Retirement Legislation File, 1977 November - August (Box 7, Folder 483)
    - Society for College and University Planning, 1978 November - 1975 October (Box 7, Folder 484)
    - Supply Conference, 1976 December - August (Box 7, Folder 485)
    - U.S.O.E. Meeting (Oct 75), 1975 November - September (Box 7, Folder 486)
    - U.S.O.E. Meeting (Jul 75), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 487)
    - 1972 Title III Material, 1972 August (Box 7, Folder 488)
    - CEFP Washington Meeting (Apr 75), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 489)
    - Conference on Student Financial Assistance for Graduate Students, 1977 February (Box 7, Folder 490)
    - CHEAR Conference - Brazil, 1977 January - 1975 July (Box 7, Folder 491)
    - Latin American Trip - Dec 1973, 1974 January - 1973 November (Box 8, Folder 492)
    - Visit to West Africa, 1969 December (Box 8, Folder 493)
    - Arlie House Meeting (Dec 76), 1978 March - 1976 January (Box 8, Folder 494)
    - Brazil Paper, 1976 August - January (Box 8, Folder 495)
    - ACE Annual Meeting (Oct 80) Speech, 1980 October - August (Box 8, Folder 496)
    - AICUM (May 80) Speech, 1980 September - May (Box 8, Folder 497)
    - CASE (Jan 80) Speech, 1980 February - 1979 December (Box 8, Folder 498)
    - SCUP (Jul 76) Speech, 1977 August - 1976 February (Box 8, Folder 499)
    - National Center for the Study of Collective Bargaining in Higher Education Speech (Apr 77), 1977 April - March (Box 8, Folder 500)
    - Graduate Student Organization of NYU Speech, 1975 July - April (Box 8, Folder 501)
    - Danforth Foundations' Institute for College Development Workshop Speech (Nov 74), 1974 November (Box 8, Folder 502)
    - Seventh Annual Conference of the Society for College and University Planning Speech (Aug 72), 1972 August (Box 8, Folder 503)
    - Faculty Urbanization File, 1976 April - 1975 September (Box 8, Folder 504)
    - Association of Governing Boards, 1980 September - 1979 December (Box 8, Folder 505)
    - Regulatory Reform in Higher Education, 1977 January - 1976 August (Box 8, Folder 506)
    - Allen Jossey-Bass Inc., Pub., 1977 June - 1976 February (Box 8, Folder 507)
    - Private Liberal Colleges, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 508)
    - Puerto Rican Problems of College Access, 1973 April - 1972 May (Box 8, Folder 509)
    - Seven Springs Papers, 1978 March (Box 8, Folder 510)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1981-1971 (Box 8, Folder 511)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 512)
    - Miscellaneous Papers, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 513)
- Correspondence Files, 1972-1979; II
  Series II, Correspondence Files (1972-1979), contains copies of correspondence generated by Mr. Crossland during his years at the Foundation. Correspondents include Ford Foundation colleagues, grantee organizations, and individuals in academia.
  This series is divided into the following three sub-series:
  A. Alphabetical Files (2 boxes) B. Chronological Files (1 box) C. Inter-Office Memoranda (1 box)
  Within each folder, the correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Alphabetical Files, A
    These files consist of Crossland's select incoming and outgoing correspondence with Ford Foundation colleagues, grantee and membership organizations, and others in academia. They are arranged alphabetically. Within each folder, the correspondence is arranged in reverse chronological order.
    - AM - AU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 514)
    - BA - BU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 515)
    - CA - CU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 516)
    - DI - DU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 517)
    - EB - EY, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 518)
    - FA - FU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 519)
    - GA - GR, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 520)
    - HA - HY, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 521)
    - IL - IV, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 522)
    - JO, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 523)
    - KA - KU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 524)
    - LA - LY, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 525)
    - MA - MO, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 526)
    - McA - McN, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 527)
    - NA - NO, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 528)
    - OA - OS, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 529)
    - PA - PI, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 530)
    - QU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 531)
    - RA - RU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 532)
    - SA - SW, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 533)
    - TA - TU, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 534)
    - VA – VO, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 535)
    - WA – WR, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 536)
    - YO, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 537)
    - Zey - F, 1979 January - June (Box 8, Folder 538)
    - AB - AS, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 539)
    - BA - BY, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 540)
    - CA - CO, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 541)
    - DA - DU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 542)
    - ED - EY, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 543)
    - FA - FU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 544)
    - GA - GR, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 545)
    - HA - HU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 546)
    - IN, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 547)
    - JA - JO, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 548)
    - KE - KO, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 549)
    - LA - LO, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 550)
    - MA - MU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 551)
    - McC - McS, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 552)
    - NA - NY, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 553)
    - O'B - OS, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 554)
    - PA - PY, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 555)
    - RA - RU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 556)
    - SA - SU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 557)
    - TH – THU, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 558)
    - UR, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 559)
    - VO, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 560)
    - WA - WY, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 561)
    - YA - YL, 1978 January - July (Box 9, Folder 562)
    - AC - AS, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 563)
    - BA - BU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 564)
    - CA - CO, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 565)
    - da - DU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 566)
    - ED, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 567)
    - FE - FU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 568)
    - GA - GU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 569)
    - HA - HU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 570)
    - IN, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 571)
    - JA - JO, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 572)
    - KA - KU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 573)
    - LA - LO, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 574)
    - MA - MY, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 575)
    - McC - McG, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 576)
    - NA - NY, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 577)
    - OL - OS, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 578)
    - PA - PO, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 579)
    - RA - RY, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 580)
    - SA - SU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 581)
    - TH - TU, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 582)
    - UN – UP, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 583)
    - VA - VO, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 584)
    - WA - WI, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 585)
    - YO, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 586)
    - Z, 1978 August - December (Box 9, Folder 587)
  - Chronological Files, B
    These files consist of Crossland's routine outgoing correspondence with Ford Foundation colleagues, grantee organizations, and individuals in academia. Within each year, the correspondence is arranged in reverse calendar order. Within each folder, they are arranged in reverse chronological order.